Brandt & Brandt Records
Brandt & Brandt Records
1935-1957
Brandt & Brandt.
2.5 linear ft.
Literary agency. Collection contains correspondence files for three American authors: Samuel Hopkins Adams, John Gunther, and Harry Hopkins.
148862
Biographical History
Brandt & Brandt was an American literary agency founded in 1914. Their clients included a number of prominent American authors, among them Samuel Hopkins Adams, Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings, Raymond Chandler and Wallace Stegner. Today the firm is known as Brandt & Hochman.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Brandt & Brandt Records contain the literary agency's correspondence files for three authors: Samuel Hopkins Adams, John Gunther, and Harry Hopkins.
Arrangement of the Collection
Within each author's file, material is arranged chronologically.
Related Material
See also the
Samuel Hopkins Adams Papers
for more Adams material.
Contract files for Brandt & Brandt for the years 1912-1995 are held by the Princeton University Manuscripts Division, http://www.princeton.edu/~rbsc.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Publishing, printing and book arts; Adams, Samuel Hopkins, 1871-1958.; Gunther, John, 1901-1970.; Hopkins, Harry.; Brandt & Brandt.; Authors and publishers.; Literary agents -- United States.; Correspondence.; Literary agents.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Brandt & Brandt, 1969, 1971.
Inventory
- Author files
  - Adams, Samuel Hopkins
    - [General], 1935-1953; 20 folders (Box 1)
  - Gunther, John
    - Advertising, 1945 (Box 1)
    - [General], 1936 (Box 1)
    - [General], 1937-1957; 25 folders (Box 2)
  - Hopkins, Harry
    - Syndication, 1945-1949 (Box 2)
    - [General], 1945 (Box 2)
    - [General], 1946-1956; 8 folders (Box 3)